RG 132, Municipal Art Society of Hartford
Connecticut State Library
Municipal Art Society of Hartford records
1903-1940
Connecticut State Library
Municipal Art Society of Hartford
2.5 cubic feet
The Municipal Art Society of Hartford was organized on June 14, 1904 in the studio of Charles Noel Flagg. Its aim was to “be of service in preserving and enhancing the beauty of our magnificent city.”
RG132
T001346
Historical Note
The Municipal Art Society of Hartford was organized on June 14, 1904 in the studio of Charles Noel Flagg. Its aim was to “be of service in preserving and enhancing the beauty of our magnificent city.” The Society was fairly active during World War I but little appears to have been done after 1920. A final meeting in June 1933 decided not to disband but nevertheless made arrangements for liquidating the accounts and transferring the Society’s records to the Connecticut State Library.
Scope and Content
The records include a constitution, minutes of meetings, reports, membership lists, accounts, correspondence, and printed materials.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Municipal Art Society of Hartford
Persons:
Flagg, Charles N. (Charles Noel)
Places:
Hartford (Conn.) -- History -- Societies, etc
Subjects:
Municipal Art Society of Hartford -- Records and correspondence; Art -- Societies, etc; Art -- Connecticut -- Societies, etc; Clubs -- Connecticut -- Hartford
Document Types:
Constitutions; Correspondence; Clippings; Bulletins; Reports; Membership lists
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1903-1940
  - 1. Constitution, 8 copies; typescript (Box 1)
    Adopted October 18, 1904.
  - 2. Minutes of meetings, 1904 June 14-1933 June 29 (Box 1)
    - 1904 June 14-1905 October 17, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1908 December 15-1933 June 29, 1 binder; typescript (Box 1)
    - 1916 October 17-1933 June 29, 1 folder; typescript copy (Box 1)
  - 3. Reports, 1904-1933 (Box 1)
    - President, Secretary & Treasurer, 1904-1914 (Box 1)
    - President, annual meeting, 1915; shared folder (Box 1)
    - President meeting, 1933 June 29; 2 copies in shared folder (Box 1)
    - Standing committees, 1904-1908 (Box 1)
    - Director's report on meeting of American Civic Association, Providence, R.I., 1907 November (Box 1)
    - Committee on baths and houses of Comfort, 1905; 1 binder (Box 1)
  - 4. Membership lists (Box 2)
    - Names of a possible membership list, undated; manuscript (Box 2)
    - Names to whom application blanks were sent in 1905, 1 notebook (Box 2)
    - Names to whom circulars were sent December 1905, 1 notebook (Box 2)
    - Names of members (Box 2)
      - 1905, 2 lists; typescript (Box 2)
      - 1917, 5 lists; typescript (Box 2)
      - 1920, 1 list; typescript (Box 2)
      - 1933, 1 list; typescript (Box 2)
    - Names of directors (Box 2)
      - 1913, 1 list; typescript (Box 2)
      - 1916-1917, 1 list; manuscript (Box 2)
  - 5. Notices, 1905-1917; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - 6. Accounts, 1 folder (Box 2)
    Contains accounts and cancelled checks.
  - 7. Miscellaneous papers, 1 bundle (Box 2)
    From Walter S. Schutz, Secretary.
  - 8. Papers of the Committee on Printing and Publication, 1904-1908; 1 folder (Box 2)
    From office of Chairman George S. Godard.
  - 9. Correspondence, 1904-1940 (Box 3-4)
    Box 3 contains a box, notebook, folder, and a folder labeled no. 1. Box 4 contains 9 folders that are labeled no. 2-9.
  - 10. Printed material (Box 5)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1 folder (Box 5)
    - Civic News, 1905-1906; 1 bundle (Box 5)
      A weekly record of public affairs of Grand Rapids and Kent County in Michigan.
    - Architects and Builders Journal, 1903 November. (Box 5)
    - Plan for restoring Old State House, 1 folder (Box 5)
    - Civic Art in Northern Europe: A Report to the Art Commission of the City of New York, Milo Roy Maltbie, 1903 October 12. (Box 5)
    - The John Crerar Library: Fifteenth Annual Report, (Chicago: 1910 ). (Box 5)
    - Inaugural Address of the President for the Year 1910, Address of the Retiring President and Annual Reports of the Standing Committees and of the Secretary fro the Year 1909 to the North Side Board of Trade in the City of New York, 1910 March. (Box 5)
    - Bulletins of the Municipal Art Society of Hartford, No. 1-16, 1904-1912 (Box 5)
      There are two copies of 1 and 16.
  - 11. Plates (Box 5)
    - Colt Park (Box 5)
    - Seal of the Municipal Art Society of Hartford (Box 5)